mncourts.gov 2019-05-23

# Minnesota Judicial Branch - Privacy Policy

Planned maintenance on the Minnesota Judicial Branch website will take place on Friday, May 24, from 8:00 p.m. to 11:00 p.m. The website may be inaccessible during that period, but all applications, such as eFile and eServe (eFS) and access to case records (MPA Remote), will still be available.

This policy addresses collection, use, and accessibility of information that may be obtained through use of the Minnesota Judicial Branch website by a website user.

  **Automatically Collected Information**  
When visiting the Minnesota Judicial Branch website, system tools and resources may automatically collect and store specific technical information about the visit. This information does not recognize the identity of the website user and is not used to track or record information specific to the individual, except when required by a law enforcement investigation. The information collected is used to provide statistical data for our website management teams who seek to determine: the information of the most and least importance to website users, the need for technical design enhancements, system performance issues, and specific problem areas. When accessing this website, the following anonymous technical information may be collected:  
• Domain and Internet Protocol (IP) address;  
• The type of browser and operating system used to access the site;  
• The files visited and the time spent in each file;  
• The time, date and duration of the visit; and  
• The referring website, if applicable.

**Voluntarily Provided Personal Information**  
The Minnesota Judicial Branch does not collect personal information of website users, unless the information is voluntarily submitted by the user. Examples of voluntarily submitted information include: (1) sending an email; (2) submitting a form through the website (3) information provided during a live chat; and (4) information provided after permitting remote computer access. The Minnesota Judicial Branch will only use voluntarily submitted personal information for its intended purpose and in an effort to assist the user in providing the information or service requested. Users submitting personal information acknowledge that providing personal information through various forms or email constitutes consent to use the information for the stated purpose.

**Cookies**  
In an effort to enhance the web browsing experience and make sessions as seamless and efficient as possible, many websites employ "cookies." Cookies are essentially small bits of software placed on a web user's hard drive by the host server. Some cookies, known as "persistent cookies" are capable of storing and maintaining the personal information of users so they will be easily recognized by the host site whenever they return. The Minnesota Judicial Branch does not use "persistent cookies." The Minnesota Judicial Branch limits its use to "session cookies" which do not permanently collect any personally-identifying information from users or to track user activities beyond the web site. These cookies are temporarily stored in the user's computer memory and are normally deleted when the user leaves the site, exits their browser, or logs off the computer.

**Public Access to Information**  
All of the information collected at this website is subject to public disclosure. Personal information provided through the website becomes public record and is subject to public inspection, unless the information is inaccessible to the public under state statute (other than Minn. Stat. ch. 13), federal law, or rule or order of the Minnesota Supreme Court.

This is a general audience website and we do not knowingly collect or request any personal information from children. Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information volunteered by children on-line or by email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.

**Contact Information**  
Visit our contact page to ask questions or provide feedback about our website polices.
